Connecting Defects to the Idea of Uncertainty
Welcome back to this session on the power of measurement.
One of the things that we are really interested in as we start to look at this relationship.
Y is a function of X in terms of measurement
is our certainty and our uncertainty over Y and X.
So, we have considerations for both Y and for X.
Where certainty and uncertainty is concerned.
Now let’s recognize, that what we're certain about, in this world,
plus everything we're uncertain about is equal to 100% of everything. It’s pretty simple.
So, certainty plus uncertainty must equal 100%. Another way of expressing that,
is that everything that we know, plus everything that is unknown
is equal to 100% of everything. That’s pretty simple.
The universe of what is unknown, plus the universe of what is known
is 100% of everything. That's the total universe.
Now another way to look at this idea, is to say that
all of our beliefs
plus all of our disbeliefs is 100%
of everything.
Now, here's another way of looking at it. Our confidence
plus our risk is equal to a hundred percent.  See, that's another way of looking at it.
Everything in this world we’re confident about, and everything else
that we believe that there is risk in. Is pretty much everything.
Here’s yet another way to look at this concept.
Yield plus the defect rate
is 100% of all production.
So, recall from an example where we looked at two operations.
Operation one had 90%. Operation two had 80%.
The throughput yield was 72%.
So, 72% plus the defect rate
of 28% has to be 100% of all units produced.
Now, it's interesting what I'm doing here. I'm measuring things.
These are measurements. These are assessments of process capability.
So, yield is confidence. Yield is a belief. Yield is what is known.
Yield is my certainty.
So, I could say that my yield is my confidence.
Which reflects my beliefs. Which describes everything that I know.
And that constitutes in this world, what I’m certain about.
On the other hand, on the flipside of that coin, I could say that my defect rate
constitutes where I'm at risk with my customer.
Which describes the extent of disbelief they have in me.
Which prescribes the extent to which I am an unknown.
Which defines my uncertainty in the marketplace.
That's an easy way that we can kind of look at this.
But here again, in order to make these statements, I need to quantify them.
And measure my belief, my disbelief, my confidence, my risk,
measure my yield, my defect rate. Isn't that interesting.
I have to measure Y and I have to measure X,
if I'm going to get a handle on the confidence and risk that I experience.
Lord Kelvin was absolutely right.
If we can't express what we know in the form of measurements.
Then we really know very little about it. And, of course Mike Harry’s corollary to that,
is if you don't know much about it. You can't control.
If you can't control it, then you are at the mercy of chance.
If you are at the mercy of chance, then your risk is uncertain.
If your risk is uncertain,
then how in the world are you steering the ship called your business.
So once again, we come to understand that measurement is everything
to defining this relationship, which is what six Sigma is all about.
Is defining our Y’s. The critical Y’s.
At the business level, operation, process level of an organization.
And then prescribing the critical X’s that controls those critical Y’s.
And measuring them to remove the risk.
To remove the uncertainty from operation of our process. To reduce our rated defects.
So as to improve our yield, to improve our confidence in the process.
That's what Six Sigma is all about.
And you can see now that Six Sigma hinges
on two fundamentally simple but critical concepts.
The first that Y is a function of X.
And the second is our ability to measure Y to measure X
so that we can establish f, the function. How the two are interrelated.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.